# **Roland Lamuel**

Entrepreneur by passion, Guitarist by heart

Mobile: +91 7708480038 Email: <u>lamuel.r92@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn URL: linkedin.com/in/roland-ed-lamuel/

#### CAREER SUMMARY

Entrepreneur & Intrapreneur, having 8+ years of startup and multi-national corporate experience in B2B and B2C sales. I possess impeccable written and verbal communication skills and excellent interpersonal skills. I am entrepreneurially driven and I look forward to solving complex business problems, applying my skill set and being a success in the organization.

### SKILLS PROFILE

- Sales and Marketing
- Entrepreneurship
- Business Strategy
- Digital Marketing
- Market Research
- Sales Strategy

- Multi- Channel Analytics
- Management Consulting
- Go To Market Strategy
- Business Model Innovation
- Business Plan/Execution
- Sales Process / Lead Generation

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# Co-founder & COO GeneBloc – Ireland / India

September 2018 to December 2021

From Idea generation and Fundraising to Product development and Market Launching, I was instrumental in all commercial, strategic planning and executions.

- Business Model Innovation & Execution
- Product Innovation Strategy & implementation
- Developed marketing collaterals such as technical Whitepaper, pitch decks, customer satisfaction surveys, etc.
- Pitched to investors at various levels like events/universities/accelerators/incubators/angel networks and won Grants.
- Market launch on an international forum
- Product testing and validation
- Team, P&L, Operations, Marketing and overall growth management.

### Head, Marketing and Sales.

May, 2018 to March 2019

**Genebox**– Dublin, Ireland.

Responsible for Sales and Marketing Strategy, Business Strategy and Execution. Reports to CEO/Founder

- Business Model analysis and innovation. Strategic business planning
- Multi-Channel Analytics Identified and developed Go to Market Strategy for B2B and B2Cchannels
- Identified and persuaded Qualified Leads through strategic process across Europe, ME and Asia
- Involved in Strategic Partnerships' with a leading Irish Health Insurer.
- Managed key stakeholders and focused towards increasing the shareholder value
- Developed Marketing Collateral/ Content/ Creative and executed Digital marketing

### Sales Manager

Nov, 2015 to May, 2017

Smith & Nephew – Chennai, India.

Managed an 8 member sales and service team, responsible for Business Development, Sales, Customer Service, Distribution Management and Customer (Orthopaedicians) Training

- Designed branding strategy for Oxinium (Prosthesis); Recognized for highest sales volume in assigned region-Chennai
- Assisted 200+ Joint Replacement Surgeries (Knee and Hip Arthroplasty); Recognized by Directors, Smith and Nephew for Innovative idea execution – Customer Service
- Organized International Conferences, Cadaver Workshops and many other training programs for Orthopaedicians
   Achieved 131% of annual sales target (USD 350,000) & 100% Market Share in 20% of focused accounts (according to 80/20 rule)

Business Manager June, 2015 to Nov, 2015

Merck Sharp and Dohme (MSD) – Chennai, India.

Responsible for Sales, Business Development and Organizing Events

- On boarded 50+ hospitals across Chennai for critical lifesaving medical drugs including key hospital chains like Apollo, Global & Fortis
- Conducted Patient Awareness programs through coordination with key hospital clients reaching out to 300+patients
- Organized 4 medical seminars best practices, anti-fungal use, infectious diseases, hospital protocol; attended by 400+ doctors

Achieved 110% of quarterly sales target (USD70,000)

# **Key Account Specialist**

July, 2013 to June, 2015

Glaxo Smith Kline (GSK) – Trivandrum, India.

Responsible for Sales, Market Research, Key corporate and government account management

- Developed a Business plan based on market research and zeroed in to a high potential account, Regional Cancer Centre, Trivandrum and introduced the high value Anti-coagulant drug to capitalize USD 120,000, yearly revenue.
- Negotiated rate contracts with top notch KOLs and succeeded in pushing high value antibiotics over generics.
- Did a field survey on product usage and brand equity and prepared a business plan based on the market insights.
- Selected in HiPot (High Potential Frontline Sales Development team, 6 out of 130 were selected), GSK
- Member of 6th Sense Squad GSK (Creative Strategy team) and awarded for implementation of risk assessment tool across 3 key hospital chains that resulted in increasing the market size and leveraging sales
   Increased the Market Size and capitalized the market potential from USD 5000 Business in 2013 to USD 23,000 by 2015.

### **EDUCATION**

## Master of Science in Entrepreneurship,

Completed Sept, 2018

Trinity College Dublin, Ireland.

- **Grade** 2.1 (68%)
- **Key Modules**: Entrepreneurship in Practice, New Company Development, Brand Management, Digital Business Model, Business Model Innovation, Entrepreneurial Finance, International Entrepreneurship.
- Paid Consulting Project: Croxha, Dublin Italy based transportation and logistics company
  - Prepared Business Plan and Investor Pitch and presented at Enterprise Ireland for funding,
  - Worked on Market Sizing, Market gap, Industry Research, Customer Insights, Operational Plan and Finance.
- **Co-Founded Cloud Closet**: Cloud closet is an online subscription-based apparel rental platform designed for young workingwomen.
  - Used *Lean Start-up methodologies* MVP was developed and validated, Customer Development process was carried out, Business model, strategic plans and the idea was pivoted and iterated based on customer validation mechanisms.
  - Identified Key Customer Segment, Identified Shift in Brand preference from Fast Fashion to Premium segments.
  - Executed Digital Marketing Strategy including Awareness Campaign through Social Media Marketing and SEO.

### Bachelor of Technology in Biotechnology,

Completed July, 2013

Kalasalingam University, India.

- **Grade** CGPA 7.12/10 (71%) First Class
- **Key Modules**: Genetic Engineering, Protein Engineering, Immunology, Molecular Biology, Bioinformatics and Computational Biology, Pharmaceutical Biotechnology, Bioprocess Engineering.
- Implant Training: On Synthesis of Nano-vesicles and Nano-particles, Transfersomes at Biolim Chennai, India.
  - On recombinant DNA Technology at Bhat Biotech Bangalore, India
- **Research Project**: "Kinetic Modelling of Fatty acid production from yeast Rhodosporidium toruloides" at Sandwoods, New Delhi, India.

### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- 2nd place in BIZZWIZZ (National level technical cum entrepreneurial presentation); Received Overall trophy -Biotechcellence'12 – Anna University CEG, Chennai
- 2nd place in National Level Technical Symposium Origene'12,India Kalasalingam University

# ADDITIONAL SKILLS AND INTERESTS

- Silver Medals in both singles and doubles title in Table Tennis at the Intra University sports meet.
- Guitarist Western Band, Inter college Cultural Fest, Kilpauk Medical College, Chennai.
- Secretary Young Talent Club (YTC), Kalasalingam University (January 2010 June 2012)
- Event Organized I'11, intercollegiate cultural fest as the Club's Secretary.
- I'm also interested in Travelling, Reading, Writing, and Pencil Sketching.

### **REFERENCES\***

- Oliver Tattan, Ireland Serial Entrepreneur & Investor, Director of Genebox
- Dr. Giulio Buciuni, Ireland Assistant Professor and Director of MSc. Entrepreneurship, Trinity College Dublin \*Available upon request